The threat of war is becoming increasingly
difficult.
Today we are living through the most dangerous moment of our time.
post-war.
Now people feel much better than
we are in nature.
In Europe, we Europeans are not
prepared to face the world as it is.
It's a tough, aggressive world,
full of challenges and we have to be
prepared to adapt to the
more difficult circumstances of
the ones we're used to.
Because we have built peace among ourselves, an extraordinary thing,
exceptional, unique in our history,
And we have believed that this peace was the normal way things happened, not
not only in Europe, but in the world.
And we don't know how lucky we are.
Now, to conclude our debate, I give the floor to the vice president and to
Representative José Porel.
Thank you, Mr. President.
Thank you to all the members who have participated in this discussion.
Josep Borrell, from Spain, is today the senior representative for human rights.
the governments, defense and vice-president
of the European Union,
a club of 27 countries that share part
of their sovereignty.
But where everyone has their own
geopolitical interests,
Their job is to try to find a single
voice.
When I proposed Borrell's name in the
negotiation,
after many days of disagreement over who should fill the positions of
responsibility,
The truth is that it came in very
naturally.
First, because he had been president of the
European Parliament,
because he had a well-established reputation as a pro-European.
It was accepted immediately.
Josep Porel, an aeronautical engineer and economist, has spent his life in the
public service,
first as a minister in several socialist governments in Spain, and then as MEP,
President of the European Parliament and now
as head of diplomacy
European.
To help him, the Treaty of Lisbon
established the creation in
2009 of the European External Action Service
a large organization.
that manages military and civilian delegations and missions around the world.
Before Borel,
It was led by Catherine Ashton of England and Federico Mogherini of Italy.
The diplomat Stefano Zanino is its director
current.
Federico,
This complex structure, which consists of 145
branches worldwide,
plus one...
The main body here in Brussels is the one
that employs more than 5,000 people that
They try to work for world peace.
The European Union is facing a complex geopolitical scenario.
a new world order in which all
participants are fighting for
to strengthen their position at a time of high risk for
democracy.
This is the chronicle of three months at the heart of European diplomacy.
Three months during Spain's rotating presidency
in which Europe faces some of its
major existential challenges,
beginning with the war in Ukraine.
Russian military forces launched an operation in neighboring Ukraine on
Friday.
Civilian and military killings have been reported.
Satellite monitoring is key for
the Union
European. The European Union Satellite Centre in Torrejón de Ardoz
It manages a network of more than 20 satellites.
They share information with their members or allies, such as the Ukrainian army.
We monitor what activities the security forces are carrying out.
If there is patrolling, if the military force is deployed, what is happening?
on the other side,
what can they expect.
There are almost a thousand reports a year about Ceuta, Melilla, and the Central Mediterranean route.
The Canary Islands, the Balkans, the eastern border.
Is this Benghazi?
Yeah.
The fact that there are two images, each with a different color, creates that three-dimensional vision.
Oh my God! You can see the ceiling!
the ceiling all the way to the bottom.
But this is incredible, isn't it?
The first time you see it, it's scary.
But that's how it seems...
Exit.
Wow, it's something else...
Josep became a real warrior, a
real Hulk, in diplomatic terms,
because,
On the one hand, he...
He has to lead a family of nations.
of
The EU, but decided to lead, not just coordinate, but lead.
And that made a big difference.
And it really made many decisions possible.
Without him we wouldn't have gotten this far.
This relationship between colleagues became
a brotherhood in arms
diplomatic.
That's how I would put it.
Of course I want peace, of course, but in the case of Ukraine I don't
Any peace will do,
I don't need just any peace.
Because I know very well how the war in Ukraine ends.
We stop helping Ukraine and the war will end in 15 days.
But how does it end?
So, how does it end?
Ukraine, the Foreign Intelligence Service, sends us its requests on
Monday morning.
And he tells us, this week, these are the
coordinates I want to cover.
Some of them in less than 24 hours.
Why are they urgent?
Because they're risking their necks.
They also give a yes or no answer.
Burel travels to Ukraine.
This is his third visit to the country since Russia's large-scale invasion in 2016.
2022.
First, the senior representative is going to
the strategic city of Odessa,
the main cover of Ukraine and a
key Ukrainian target.
If Odessa falls, the country's access to the sea
would be cut off.
Russia, especially over the last year, has been attacking, carrying out
night air raids,
that combine drones, we have seen Iranian drones,
Therefore, in a city like that, the alternative
of what was once normal in Ukraine is found.
of the new Russian invasion,
And at the same time, that normality can be
destroyed at a moment when they fail
air defenses,
Because Russia attacks with drones almost all the time, and with missiles too.
You see people here, but when they're in this place,
They're still nervous because the attack
could happen in
any time.
Any public space could be Russia's next military target.
The locals know the rules well.
They make the most of the sun before the night's heat.
These bombings often originate from the
Crimean Peninsula,
occupied by the Russians in 2014.
They seek to break the morale of the inhabitants by destroying the most important places.
symbolic,
like the city's historic cathedral.
Russian propaganda claimed these were
missile debris
Russian anti-aircraft guns.
But you can see the destruction that has been caused.
Waste cannot cause this destruction.
Russian attacks are focused on crippling
the national economy by preventing the
grain remains in the Black Sea.
It tries to destroy all of Ukraine's means of survival.
which is an export-oriented economy and which
needs to export.
But thanks to Ukrainian military audacity,
which also benefits from
Western support,
Ukraine is now able to export grain at levels almost prior to the start of the
invasion.
We are passing through Odessa,
because in Odessa we have deployed a
mission to support the security forces
from Ukraine,
not military, but from the police.
They left with the invasion, they've returned
now, they've settled in Odessa,
and also to learn how Ukrainian society is experiencing the situation in which
this.
Lately,
We have recorded many cases of sexual violence in our
men in war.
And here we're talking about torture.
There are 250 cases of sexuality,
of which there are 85 men,
150 women, 13 non-adults, 12 girls and one
child.
Because we understand that everyone, absolutely everyone,
We are in a state of post-traumatic syndrome.
And it's also sending a strong signal to
Russia.
Just after I left Odessa, a
new drone kingdom falls on the oblast of
Odessa.
We are not intimidated by your drones or missiles.
Our resolution to support the struggle
for the freedom and independence of Ukraine
is firm and
will continue.
How are you?
How was your day?
A very long day, isn't it?
Always, always.
Well, we need to make sure that what's happening isn't harassment.
How are you doing?
I'm going to take a bath now.
What can I tell you?
We've got a real bombshell coming next week.
From the rain.
Whenever you arrive here, your perception changes, and it's also exciting.
when we went to the opera.
How does life go on, and if we can't do opera at night, why will they do it?
bombings, they do during the day.
A few kilometers, hundreds of kilometers
and now they're arriving right in front of us.
Life goes on.
Ukraine is under existential threat and
they somehow pay tribute to the
fallen.
It must be understood that they respect the Armed Forces and figures within them.
Armed forces that are often made up of volunteers,
directors, electricians, plumbers,
etc.
And for them, well, like heroes.
In Independence Square they place a
small flag as a sign of respect and as a sign
of appreciation for the dead in
the war.
They are mostly volunteers who died
helping Ukraine, they died fighting for
Ukraine.
Unfortunately, the number of flags
has grown over the past few years and
half.
It makes no sense to have discussions about
relations with Russia.
Because today Russia is the greatest danger to
Europe.
It's not a patch, it's a problematic patch
that you have to build with.
relations.
He's an enemy, he's a danger, and you have to treat him accordingly.
Thank you to Ukraine! Thank you
Ukraine
You find the remains of tanks and cars in several Ukrainian cities.
Russians.
The Russian army had made preparations
for military parades in kyiv.
And well, the joke the Ukrainians have is that the only parades for
Now, thankfully, thank God, they are from
the destroyed Russian tanks.
Putin was crazy.
Putin?
And not?
Putin, you jerk.
It's popular, I've said here.
The first diplomatic crisis that Borel
had to face when he took office
It was the controversy generated by his
request to
Visiting the anti-regime dissident, Alexei Navalny, who was printed in Russia.
The European media accused him of meddling in Russian internal affairs.
He was heavily criticized, and not only by
his Russian partner, Sergey Lavrov.
Since then,
the senior representative has
turned into an escapee for
Russian propaganda.
Barrel, enemy of the Russian people.
I want it written on his engraving: Here
remembers the enemy of the Slaves,
the enemy of the Russian people, the enemy of
humanity.
Satanism, a little demon.
There were always voices saying, "Let's not get involved,"
but in this case it doesn't affect us.
Yes, I'll go into their house.
Because?
Because there are international laws respecting human rights, because there are
agreements that you have signed and I have too,
and we had to go there at the exact moment when
Navalny was sitting in front of the
court to put our rejection on the table
the way Russian political power is
behaving with this man who some
years later
He died in Siberia in a camp...
who will not be able to win the war,
It depresses us about Western weapons and that
it gives us fatigue and
desire to support Ukraine.
Russia is doing a lot in the fight against
information.
We see it in the Sahel.
When I see these young African women
coming with big guns,
They say the public has saved Donbas.
What a great idea! In Brussels,
a team led by the German
Lutz
Kuhlner fights against
the strategies of
disinformation.
that threaten Europe's fragile internal balances.
The service isn't very big, but there are still
40 people.
And what we really do is
understanding, analyzing the bad
information and,
In particular, the manipulation of information.
It's not just the breadth of certain
contents, but it goes much further.
It is the use of certain techniques to achieve
a large magnification, for example.
Doppelganger is an example of how these campaigns work.
In this case, social media accounts are copied
from media outlets with a very good reputation,
For example, The Spiral, The Guardian, Le Monde.
But it's very easy to get hooked on social media.
People who went to these social networks
thought they were reading the
through their reference,
but it is found in another medium where
content is exchanged.
And so, as someone who cannot see this,
he becomes somewhat of an accomplice,
because it starts sharing this content, and it's unconscious.
In other words, it becomes part of this
system.
We see Russian actors in the background,
especially strong ones.
Since Russia's war of attack against
Ukraine, they are even clearer.
But there are also other actors, such as, for example, the Chinese, whom we have identified.
And we must not forget that there are also
non-state actors, such as organizations
terrorists, such as DASH,
that use the same techniques.
The European Union's Foreign Affairs Council meets to discuss the support that
We're going to give it to Ukraine,
economic, military and diplomatic.
I propose a new bilateral, multi-year agreement within the European Peace Facility.
up to
5 trillion for next year.
In Singular, more is coming.
We will continue training Ukrainian soldiers.
The goal today is to train 40,000 people in the next month.
And this includes specialized training
for airplane pilots.
And we will continue working on
resilience, the defense of the
cybersecurity and defense against hybrid threats,
such as disinformation and the development of
common strategic communications.
It is very important to increase our support
for the demining.
This is a key condition for the
economic recovery and reconstruction of
Ukraine.
We started this war as friends who
deserved help,
but they were not part of the family.
And now there's a completely different tone
in the content of the discussion,
because they are discussing helping a
family member,
help get out of the biggest threat that
this family member is
facing.
When the European Council decided
to consider Ukraine as a candidate,
You know, at first it was quite
difficult to say, oh, great, it's a great country,
In war, are they prepared or not?
But once we crossed the Rubicon, once
we decided that they're going to put you in,
So everyone is pushing.
And yes, surely the classic reform that any democracy has to undertake is necessary.
to do to fulfill the
European standards.
But you will do it because on your side too,
it is clear that the European path...
For us and for many others
in Europe, Ukraine is coming back.
Returning from Russian captivity.
Astonishingly, what President Putin did,
presenting himself as the advocate of this
traditional civilization that is different
from
the European one, he caused the contrary
effects,
he gave us space to cut off all the
connections with him, with Russia,
and return to where we belong, which is
Europe.
To avoid wars, we must get rid of the
black zones.
And it's very clear why there's a war in
Ukraine now.
because they are not part of the European Union and
they are not part of NATO.
So they're in this bold zone and the
aggressor thinks they're very weak and that
They can expand their empire.
Weakness creates aggressors, not strength.
The war against Ukraine has been the big issue for Europe.
Yes, we are a soft power in the sense that
our weapons are the State of
Law and commerce.
But now the world has become a little
more complicated.
And I believe that with that alone we won't get anywhere,
or we'll only get very far.
and we run the risk of sinking.
And today we are writing a new
page.
in defense of the European Union.
Today we are at the first time that an exercise is being carried out
military alongside the European Union.
In Cádiz, joint movements are taking place
for the first time outside the country.
The world is in the midst of an arms race, and the Atlantic Alliance demands that
European countries increase
significantly
their defense expenses.
The plan is to have a reaction force
fast.
But the embryo of a European army
future?
The European Union is an economic
or geopolitical alliance.
But it is clear that all European countries need to strengthen their defenses.
which also strengthens NATO as a whole.
The war in Ukraine has confronted us with
a very terrible reality, that there is
wars, that there are conventional wars,
that there are wars from the last century and that
we are very vulnerable.
Reaching 2% of GDP in defense is very important.
Investing in defense is investing in peace, freedom, security, and values.
democratic.
There is nothing more important than that.
Many of those who oppose military spending, when push comes to shove,
They complain that we have not been able to
intervene in Syria.
Okay, but how were we going to intervene in
Syria?
With a slingshot, that is, if you want
intervention, it's because you have
capabilities, right?
If he doesn't have them, then he has to be
dependent on someone else who does.
Today, he dares to speak of European defense.
The war has been an additional factor, of course, but I want to emphasize the fact
that it really started earlier and that the
Europeans
There has been a gradual realization
that all the buildings had to be constructed
tools...
of their autonomy, of their capacity to act
as they wish, in whatever way they wish,
as an economic, political, and industrial power, but also having the
means of defending themselves and their interests.
Some EU27 axes participate in military missions around the world, such as
Atalanta,
to fight piracy in the Gulf
of Aden, Irini, against the mafias
immigrants in the Mediterranean,
or the Aspites,
to protect European ships
against attacks in the Red Sea.
such as Spain, such as
Portugal or Italy, we have others
different geographical concerns, for example,
the situation in the Sahel, and we have to
be able to harmonize that.
It's not easy because, obviously, each country tends to look at its own affairs.
peculiarities.
There have been many other moments, coups in the Sahel, the civil war in
Ethiopia,
the permanent instability in the Horn of Africa.
Africa is one of the most complex scenarios for a Europe that is
stripped bare by its colonial past and struggling to maintain its influence
strategic in Russia and China.
The European Union establishes refugee camps and reinforces its military presence
democratic governments like that of Ghana,
threatened by a wave of coups d'état in the region.
Borel comes to offer military equipment.
The 105 militarized vehicles and other critical defense equipment have been
donated.
The Ghanaian Armed Forces and other security agencies
are worth about 20 million euros
and
are funded by the
European Peace Facility.
The senior representative is moving to China.
The Asian giant is the silent elephant in the geopolitical arena, a
key player in the new multipolar order.
The trade relationship is very unbalanced.
And we have to find the balance between
remaining
open and reduce the
risk.
China also doesn't quite understand the
intrinsic reality, for example,
of the war between Russia and Ukraine.
They have influence over Russia, a lot of influence over Russia.
They've said they have a friendship without limits, although when it comes down to it...
All friendships have limits.
And from this contest, Russia will emerge
weakened and China will most likely be strengthened
in its geopolitical role.
I buy gas, you buy my products,
we're good friends and we're all in the same boat
happy.
Well, we're all happy until
the virus comes or the war starts.
Not everyone is happy.
But from the point of view of defending
these socioeconomic rights,
We are much more advanced than you.
Sorry, we're more like colleagues than you are.
It's not easy to say.
Because we take 40% or 50% out of people's pockets.
of their wealth and we redistribute it in society.
And we have a pension system, a public health system, and a public education system that is,
we can say,
more collectivist than ours.
And we believe that the basic things of
human life are not for the
market.
It's not a policy, it's a society.
And just these days, a new conflict
enters the scene,
another major challenge for European diplomacy.
October 7th was a tragic day for the State of Israel.
It was the best day for the people of It was the
best day for the people of the Jewish community since
the Holocaust.
More than 3,000 terrorists joined Israel.
More than 1,400 people died.
Among them, children, babies, the whole family.
The batteries of war are starting to sound in the Middle East.
The Foreign Service activates the Crisis Committee, coordinated by the diplomat
Spanish Francisco Fontán.
When we enter a crisis, we have a
special focus of information and there we
we turned a little bit into a
fusion instrument.
information from the house that has the diplomatic terminal,
a defense terminal and an intelligence terminal.
So, use those three terminals in a more or less tactical way.
And then we are constantly preparing
for the possibility of an evacuation of both
European citizens as well as our diplomats on the ground.
If that happens, the movement from the embassy to the port will be quite noticeable.
and complicated.
So we need to continue thinking and working on that and developing all
the maps.
All the plans are there, the solutions are in place, the C.P.O.s, the vehicles of
weapon.
Yeah.
Urel continues to monitor China's attacks.
How many more times has he committed crimes?
To begin with, are you asking them to condemn themselves?
Nobody talks about Ukraine.
It seems as if in our media universe we are only capable of
digest one crisis at a time.
And now they see that we, well, suddenly,
have the attention of the Middle East,
Because in every European country there are
Palestinian communities, there are communities
beans.
In any case, for us, the Western world,
This raises a problem of respect for the values ​​we defend.
The damage from terrorist attacks is clear
here in Europe, but also throughout the world
world.
So the overall level of alert and
contact with colleagues in the
The floor needs to be maintained.
We can't just focus on what's happening in the
not only the Middle East, but also the impact of the Middle East on the rest of the world.
to see a little bit what is happening.
So they have a responsibility
to create a flow of information about it
that happens all over the world at all times.
This is information that we share with
all Member States and with others
partners such as the African Union or the United Nations
and
with a special focus when there is a particular crisis.
Israel responds with a large-scale attack in northern Gaza.
The escalation threatens to destabilize
the entire Arab world.
We have failed miserably to make the
two-state solution anything more than
just a slogan to be
repeated at all international meetings.
We are in favor of the two-state solution, yes, we are.
And then what?
But now perhaps is the time for
the international community to react.
This has to be done with the complete
deception of the Arab world and it
can mobilize the European side.
Back from China, Borel is
in line with EU27 leaders to
try to reconcile
about a common message.
The danger lies in a possible connection between
the war fronts in Ukraine and the
Middle East.
The international community and the EU should not lose their focus on the
main topics.
Israel has simply prevented the two-state solution
with its unlawful measures and
laterals.
Now, the question that should be asked is whether it isn't a two-way solution
States, so what?
And then it will become a reality
of a state.
And the reality of a state will not be a solution, it will be a cursed reality.
characterized by apathy,
which will be a recipe for a bigger conflict.
In Gaza, the dead are beginning to be named
among the thousands of people.
The desperation of the civilian population
is growing, accompanied by a
growing scarcity of resources.
The shoulders of the European Union are
being displaced by
this new crisis.
In the European Union, Germans, Australians, checks, and Italians
They vote differently from the other European members.
The wounds of history are taking their toll.
toll.
Hamas is a terrorist organization that must be fought.
that Israel has the right to self-defense,
and that this right to self-defense must
to be carried out within the framework of international humanitarian law.
But for me there is one fundamental condition: if I visit Israel, I must be able to
also visit Ramallah.
Well, it's a conflict that has lasted for more than 50 years.
and that it is not only divisive among governments, but even among the
their own societies, and not only in
Europe, but also in the world.
In any case, I believe Pepe Borrell's position is consistent.
consistent with the same position we have in Ukraine.
I recommend that you read the Practical Dictionary of Humanitarian Law.
Where it is clearly stated that depriving a community of its basic water supply
human under siege is
contrary to international law.
In Ukraine and in Gaza.
And if we are not able to say it in both places,
We lack the necessary moral authority
to make our voice heard.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, Representative Borrell.
Israel's best friend is not the one who gives him carte blanche.
is the one who warns him of the
consequences of sowing more hatred and
repeat that cycle of
violence.
Europe is divided on this issue,
because there are different countries with different
sensitivities, explainable by their
history.
Everyone is against the Holocaust and against antisemitism.
But others feel more responsible.
There is clearly a guilt complex
expressed in some countries that don't want
that
place no limits on Israel, so that its
right to self-defense can be exercised without
boundaries.
I think the current crisis is one of the most complicated that has ever been for
all of us,
for all institutions, for all
Member States.
This refers to many factors that are not yet...
...okay, necessarily.
But that's the story of the European Union.
It's clear that in every crisis, at the beginning, it's always said that the Union
Europe is divided,
that there is no more European Union...
It is being built.
On many occasions I have spoken about the crises of the European Union, about the
difficulties that the European Union faces,
because of the slowness in decision-making by the European Union, but the processes
democratic,
In this case, it takes 27 member states
time, but it eventually happens.
The highest-ranking representative begins his most delicate journey.
a journey where every gesture and every word counts to preserve the
balance.
The risk of the conflict spreading throughout the Arab world is a serious threat.
for Europe.
I have to somehow overcome a certain accusation of being pro-Palestinian.
I am neither pro-Palestinian nor pro-Israeli;
I must seek peace between those two.
villages that are fighting over the same land.
That they respect each other and live in freedom and dignity, each one of them.
without having to go through this succession of violence, and if we don't succeed...
Well, the spiral of hatred will continue to grow, and we'll go from funeral to funeral and
of
deaths upon deaths in knowing when this
can be stopped.
The high-ranking representative, accompanied by the Israeli Minister for the United Nations,
Eli Cohen,
Visit one of the kibitzum on attack.
There is only one party responsible for this
atrocity, and that is Hamas.
They are not human.
We are monsters and we should all be united to liberate Gaza from Hamas.
for the security of the State of Israel.
For the people of Gaza and for the whole world.
If not, Europe will be next.
Thank you so much.
Minister, allow me to say something that doesn't come from this document, but from the part
lower part of my heart.
I understand your fears and your pain.
I understand the fears and pain of the
people who have been attacked, killed,
murdered.
I understand your laughter.
But let me ask you not to be
consumed by rage.
That's what Israel's best friend
can tell you.
Because what makes the difference between a civilized society and a group
Terrorism is the lack of respect for human life.
We cannot bring life to death,
But we can give freedom to the hostile.
On the same day, a meeting is held with
the families of the hosts killed by
Hamas.
Imagine, someone you love, just one person.
It can be your son, your daughter, your grandmother, your
wife, your husband, just one.
But imagine this: shooting, recording in different languages,
RPG for your children, for your love that
you think about now.
Imagine that.
Please.
It's a screenshot from a propaganda video
that Hamas published.
We saw my brother scared, humiliated,
heading.
It's crazy that we're grateful to
see him like this, in a video, alive.
And that's how we want to receive it again.
We don't have time to die over the dead.
because we just want them to go back home.
It's unforgettable, so I'm really asking that, you know,
We just need an agreement, and we know that
there can be one.
I never felt more powerful than at that moment.
To have the ability to...
...of...
I want to ask you something.
I believe Qataris are the main
countries influencing Hamas.
There's the money budget, the
humanitarian budget, and if Qatar says to
Sinoa,
This murderous man, stop him now,
keep them all out,
They can do it.
Your pressure is not simple in Qatar,
But Qatar needs its reputation in the Arab world, and they need its reputation in
Europe.
And Europe, that's you.
I feel devastated when I walk into school, and you think about the children there.
there were
murdered.
But of course, five kilometers away
they're bombing Gaza and they're also
dying
Every day children under the bombs.
Therefore, one horror does not justify another.
I come from a part of the world, from the
European Union,
that for years we have been fighting
against terror, devastating, killing,
almost committing suicide.
And in the end we make reconciliation.
And today you can travel from Gibraltar to the Arctic without crossing any borders.
The border, Mr. President,
It is the burden that history has been
carrying on the Earth's framework.
And we have to overcome it.
And we have to do this, not only between
Israel and the Arab countries,
but between Israel and Palestine.
Good morning, friends.
We are very happy to have a representative with us this morning.
He really wanted to come and pay a quick visit to the EU delegations.
The Union
The European Union currently has 145 delegations
throughout the
world that carry out diplomatic activities and work with the association
of each country, acting de facto as
European embassies.
In the Jerusalem delegation, the tension
of the conflict is palpable.
We have many Christians here, among the
colleagues, who would like to say, tension,
You can feel it if you walk through the old city,
The tension is very high.
If you are Palestinian, you will be arrested by the IDF police.
Especially at night, there's a tension
out there.
Palestinian support has been reduced to humanitarian needs.
Instead of focusing on what we need, it's the international lawyer.
Nothing else.
We want to talk to you more.
It's a very short time.
We can accompany you in our homes.
Shirin, please.
But he wants to hear from us.
But he has a plan.
He has to go to Ramallah.
Please, Shirin.
As promised in Parliament, Borel
begins his first tour as a leader
European to Palestinian territory from
the beginning of the war.
The most complicated step is the meeting with
the main NGOs at the Bank of
West. The tension caused by the struggles
of the Palestinian population with the
inhabitants and the Israeli army, and, above all,
due to the increased bombing of Gaza, it is
extremely high.
Every four minutes now a Palestinian is killed, and every ten minutes a child is killed.
killed.
We're all talking about what comes next,
we need to talk about what's happening now
now.
We have a right to the jungle, not to the
international.
And that has to stop.
Another thing that worries us a lot is the
level of the double standard.
Why in the case of Ukraine is all this support going to Ukraine because it is
fighting against the
occupation, and in our case, the support goes to
the occupiers, not the employed?
I understand your frustration.
And I understand there are two decisions regarding
this.
When I have to bring the resolution to the 27th
and I need unanimity, I have to compose.
We have been fighting for two states
for more than three decades.
And nothing has been done.
negotiations, procrastination,
coercion, diplomacy.
You don't want to recognize the Palestinian state.
I hear you, but I don't remember you.
But if you want to be practical, please
call on Israel to end the occupation
Israeli military.
But not because of my rhetoric.
Because I love your rhetoric, I really do,
I keep following.
Let Israel bring its borders,
but we shouldn't tolerate seeing Netanyahu
at the UN,
grabbing the map from the sea to the
sea and then falling silent.
They have to stop the atrocity.
The crime of collective punishment, the crime of ethnic cleansing, and the crime
of the
violence.
Yes, but, you know what?
It makes us very frustrated and short on resources, because
you have a meeting that's only an hour and a half long,
Once it's over, I don't have time to
discuss.
This issue of the right to self-determination
for the Palestinian people
will maintain.
That's what we have to do.
But now we need to try to find
concrete things we can do to
get out of this
back of life.
People in the Palestinian territory have
seen in the last 30 years that they have
done and broken the
treaties that have been made but have not been maintained.
And we have seen that the occupation is becoming more entrenched with more settlements,
more land confiscation,
More home demolitions and more pronounced Israeli policy that undermines the
right of the Palestinian people to
reduction and inequality.
In the absence of military power, the EU
exerts its diplomatic influence through
of their economic power.
It is the main financier of the Palestinian National Authority.
as it should be in the reconstruction of
Gaza when the war is over.
The delegation of high-ranking representatives
now faces the final leg of the journey,
Doha.
Qataris are key players in many of the recent agreements between countries
predominantly Muslim and the
west.
The possibility of securing a pair of briefs in Gaza will mark the success of their mission to
the Middle
East.
Mr. Prime Minister, I am sure that
you will do everything you can to free
These hostile ones.
For our part, the European Union is
doing exactly the same thing.
putting pressure on both sides to
make this agreement possible.
We are close to reaching an agreement that
can
take people home,
whether it's the Hamas hosts or any other exchange that might occur.
Important things that shouldn't be relevant to the agreement itself, but if the
The agreement will make it easier,
We hope it happens as soon as possible.
Qatar and the European Union see a humanitarian pause very close to Gaza.
Hamas and Israel join forces to exchange 50
hostiles in exchange for 150 prisoners
Palestinians.
Burel and his team returned to Brussels
to explain the agreement with the Union
European 27.
The European Union is a structure that
is always based on a fragile balance.
A Europe that seems to function better on the front lines of threats, such as Brexit,
the pandemic or Ukraine.
A Europe that perhaps still finds it
too difficult to explain to its
citizens.
Everything depends on the ability to react
to the crisis.
But anticipating a crisis and acting
with the expectation that something might happen,
That proactive attitude; we are much more
reactive.
Therefore, we will be what the world forces us to be.
The United States Congress
unlocks $61 million in aid
for Ukraine.
Israel has been attacked by 170
large...
The victims of the attack on Damascus...
Geopolitical crises are advancing at a frenetic pace.
The question is whether a future union of 600 million people, with its enormous
organizational complexity,
a Europe that is still caught up in
nation-states, that finds it difficult to
serenity,
will have the tools to deal with the
new multipolar and globalized world.
I don't know if history will accelerate or reverse.
What I do know is that the founding fathers
surely didn't imagine that the Europe that
they conceived
was to go as far as it has gone.
Everyone is going to Tel Aviv, asking them not to do it; they are protecting civilians.
Don't kill so many.
How many is that?
What is the standard?
But Netanyahu doesn't listen to anyone.
They are going to be evacuated.
Where?
By Monday?
Well, if you think so many people are being killed,
Perhaps you should offer fewer weapons.
In short, to prevent so many people from being murdered, it's not logical.